<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DynDNS on Peter&#39;s Notebook</title>
    <link>https://peterlavalle.github.io/tags/dyndns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DynDNS on Peter&#39;s Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://peterlavalle.github.io/tags/dyndns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi3 NameCheap</title>
      <link>https://peterlavalle.github.io/post/pi3-namecheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peterlavalle.github.io/post/pi3-namecheap/</guid>
      <description>This is a followup to a previous post because that one stopped working, now - this works.
There&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of OC here, just clarity.
NameCheap DynDNS on a Pi3 I use NameCheap (because they&amp;rsquo;re anti-SOPA) for DNS. The client program, ddclient, can connect to NameCheap.
I&amp;rsquo;m using raspbian, so, first;
 run sudo apt-get install ddclient on your Pi find the dynamic DNS settings on NameCheap&amp;rsquo;s website  Dashboard &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Domain List &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Manage &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Advanced DNS they do like to change these things around  halfway down the page, there should be a DYNAMIC DNS thingie  enable it (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already) note the blurb-what-looks-like-a-SHA  edit your /etc/ddclient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi3 DynDNS</title>
      <link>https://peterlavalle.github.io/post/pi3-dyndns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peterlavalle.github.io/post/pi3-dyndns/</guid>
      <description>This has been replaced
Pi3 DynDNS I want to give my home&amp;rsquo;s Raspberry Pi3 a DNS name so that I can access it more easily.
DNS and Dynamic IP Addresses The Domain Naming System is how those readable textual names like example.com become the actual IP Addresses like 127.0.0.1 that web pages, email, and everything else needs to work. Various groups allow people to register a domain (or subdomain) and specify the IP address of a computer that the domain should reffer to.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>